Abraham Odubena

+2348145363771 · odubenaabraham201@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> Lagos, Nigeria.

Recent graduate with experience in deploying and maintaining hardware systems. I'm proficient in installing, configuring and troubleshooting advanced security systems ensuring that hardware operates efficiently and meets safety standards.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Networking & Communication Protocols.
- Proficient with ZKTeco software systems.
- Programming.
- Hardware Installation & Configuration.
- · Troubleshooting.
- Rockwell Automation

SOFT SKILLS

- I'm an active participator when collaborating with others.
- I point out ideas that can foster better results.
- I'm disciplined.
- I prioritize time management.
- Ever learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nestle Nigeria | Information Technology & Engineering Automation Dept NYSC Intern

Sept 2024 - Present

- Provided technical support for hardware, software, and networking issues.
- Ensured Optimal Performance of systems used in Manufacturing, Logistics, and office environments.
- Managed IT systems including servers, databases, and cloud platforms.
- Monitored System Performance and ensure system availability and reliability
- Maintained security Protocols and ensure systems comply with internal and external regulations.
- Worked with security teams to manage risks and handle incidents.
- Conduct training sessions for employees on new systems or technologies.
- Designed and implemented network communications between PLCs, production lines, switches, and routers to optimize system integration.
- Configured and installed Allen Bradley NATR (Rockwell Automation) modules for seamless automation processes.
- Diagnosed and troubleshooted production line inefficiencies, identifying and resolving bottlenecks to improve overall productivity and system performance.
- Managed and maintained hardware for biometric access control and attendance systems (ZKTeco and SOCA) to ensure secure and efficient employee management.
- Conducted routine system upgrades and maintenance to reduce downtime and enhance system reliability, ensuring consistent production workflow.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite, with a focus on data management and reporting for automation-related tasks.

GOMYCODE Jan 2023 – Jun 2023

Full Stack Developer Intern

(6 Months)

- Developed a video chat application web app.
- Built experience in project management (how to properly schedule projects, understand the requirements of stakeholders and align solutions to tailor to their needs).

CT Digital Dec 2022 - Jun 2023

Full Stack Developer Intern

(6 Months)

- Worked closely with the Product designer to build a streamlined event management website where clients could book events making registration process faster and less tedious. The site was fully responsive and developed with html, css and javascript.
- Integrated a discount page section for a clinic web app where patients could genrate coupons as discount codes.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Computer Sci

2019 - 2023

Lagos State University

Program Coursework - Data Structures. Object Oriented Programming. Operating Systems. Algorithms

REFEREES

Available on Request